Well today I am looking at what I believe is the sweet spot in the Honda Civic line if
you are an enthusiast driver. This is the Honda civic SI.
It is the 4-door sedan. The SI is also available in the 2-door coupe. You cannot get it in the hatchback.
You get a sport model or the sport touring but it doesn’t have the same engine as this and of course in the hatch
you  can get the type R which adds another 100+ horse power but that is 40,000$ car and
it doesn’t have the looks that’s would ever appeal to me in fact I don’t think that the hatchbacks are great looking
Honda civic. I think that the coupe and the sedan are much better looking in my opinion.
A lot of it comes down to how busy the new civic is with the hatchback you get a blunt rear end.
You get all the black cladding along the bottom of the bumper looks like a cheese grater.
You get it with this car too but it seems to integrate a little bit better with the type R there is wings
there is fins there is all of this cladding on it that just is not going to appeal to a certain segment of the market
for me personally I would rather have a much more subdued looking car like a Volkswagen golf R
or a WRX something like that. So this is really why I think this is the sweet spot so with the SI in the sedan you get
18 inch wheels, you get a spoiler around the back of the car, you get a center exhaust tip which really
looks unique and sporty and it has a nice look to it. It definitely looks good with this black and
blue contrasting colors and yes you still get those cheese grater effects on the front lower valance
and the rear of the bumpers which looked like a after thought but they are done to anchor the car and
make it look like it’s part of the road. I am not going to talk too much about the civic because it's
been out for couple of years. It won the car of the year, North American car of the year.
It’s a wonderful product touch on what’s different on the inside but the biggest
part of the story is what it's like to live with every single day.
Notice as I mentioned I am not going to talk too much about the car generally because
it’s been out for couple of years and won all kinds of awards. One thing about civic it's big.
This is bigger than the original accord was and when the Si is equipped, you get the nicely bolstered
SI seats in cloth which is great for gripping you get the aluminum pedals underneath them you get a nice feeling
manual shifter and an excellent cockpit seating position in Honda's has always been first rate especially
in this civic line and this one is no different. One thing I am not crazy about with the manual transmission,
I just thought of it when I started up you have an electronic parking brake switch here which I am not
loving with any manual transmission car. Okay. So two generations ago they used to have a 2 liter
very highly strung engine in the SI. It is a really wind it out. I called it a cat on caffeine. Yeah it was like
ready to pounce at any time and I never really liked that car because it  had no bottom and torque and
it had to ring out the engine and get it really going in a big way to get the most out of it.
So, what did civic do was it Honda do with the civic SI